

IYER AADITHYA

Mechatronics Student at FH Aachen

+49 17655270982





in www.linkedin.com/in/aadi thya-iyer-611544124

About Me

I have one and a half year work Experience with and Prototype Designing testing of Electric Vehicles

I was a part of my college Formula Student Team for two years

Hobbies: Motorsports, Karting, Road trips

Responsibilities

Executive Design Engineer, Mahindra Electric

Powertrain Team Member and Graphics Head, Team Orion Racing India

Creative **Head-**Mechanical Council

Skills

Electric Vehicle Battery Pack Design, DFMEA, DMU, Poka Yoke, Thermal and Structural Simulation, Testina (2017-2019)

Catia CAD Designing and Ansy<u>s</u> Simulation for the Intake and Exhaust system of Gasoline Engines (2015-2017)

Education

Master of Science September, 2019 - today

Bachelor of Engg. June. 2013 - Juli 2017

College March, 2011-March, 2013

> School February, 2011

Fachhochschule Aachen Mechatronics (Third Semester)

KJ Somaiya (Mumbai University) Mechanical Engineering (210 credits) German Grade: 1.56 (CGPI: 8.88/10)

PACE Junior Science College, Powai

Science HSC: 85.83%

Bombay Scottish School, Powai

Elective: Computer Science ICSE: 87.57%

Work Experience



June, 2018 - Sept, 2019

Mahindra Electric Mobility Limited

Profile: Design engineer for battery

research and development

Project: Development of battery pack concepts, perform DMU and DFMEA, assist in structural and

thermal analysis, prototype testing



Team Orion Racing India 2016 - 2017

Formula Student Team, 2017

Role: Designing, simulating, manufacturing and testing of the intake and exhaust system of a two-

cylinder Gasoline engine

Competitions: FS Germany, FS Italy



Team Orion Racina India 2015 - 2016

Formula Student Team, 2016

Project: Assist in the designing, manufacturing and testing of Formula-prototype Race cars and participate in static and dynamic events at the competition

Competitions: FS Germany, FS India



Tata Motors Pvt. Ltd. June - July, 2015

Internship

Division: Tata Sumo BIW

Project: Compare CO2 welding with spot welding process and replace it. Design Fixtures for the spot welding process. Provide solutions to reduce spot welding costs by reducing spool consumption



Technical Paper 2nd Place - PRAKALP 2016

German: B2 from Goethe Institute







Software Skills







